<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Beichen Zhang</title>
    <link>https://zhang-beichen.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Beichen Zhang</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://zhang-beichen.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>AGU 2023 🌎</title>
      <link>https://zhang-beichen.github.io/archive/agu2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zhang-beichen.github.io/archive/agu2023/</guid>
      <description>AGU Fall Meeting 2023 is coming. I will serve as a chair of the GeoHealth (GH23): Surviving the Dry Spell: Understanding the Connection Between Drought Health, which will be held from 14:10 to 15:40 on December 12. Here is the abstract of the session.
Drought is a natural disaster that can have a profound impact on the environment, economy, and human health. Droughts can lead to food and water scarcity, malnutrition, water-borne diseases, and increased environmental hazards, such as smoke, dust, and heat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes of ChatGPT Prompt Engineering for Developers</title>
      <link>https://zhang-beichen.github.io/archive/dlai_chatgpt_prompt_engineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zhang-beichen.github.io/archive/dlai_chatgpt_prompt_engineering/</guid>
      <description>For ease of referring and checking in the future, I summarized this outline for the short course ChatGPT Prompt Engineering for Developers at DeepLearning.AI.
Introduction Introducing the general background of natural language process (NLP) with deep learning (DL).
Large language models (LLMs) [I think here the term refers to GPT-like LLMs] were categorized into two types.
Base LLM
Predicts the next word based on the training data Instruction Tuned LLM</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AMS 2023 ⛅️</title>
      <link>https://zhang-beichen.github.io/archive/ams2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zhang-beichen.github.io/archive/ams2023/</guid>
      <description>The interdisciplinary research on predicting and assessing complex drought impacts using explainable ML will be presented as a talk at the session: 8A.3 Trustworthy AI at 4:15 PM - 4:30 PM on Tuesday, January 10 in the AMS 2023 annual meeting. Welcome to stop by and join the session! Slides of the presentation at AMS 2023. If you are interested in this research and have any further questions or comments, please also feel free to contact me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AGU 2022 🌎</title>
      <link>https://zhang-beichen.github.io/archive/agu2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zhang-beichen.github.io/archive/agu2022/</guid>
      <description>The preliminary research on studying the impacts of climate extremes, particularly droughts, on the increased frequency will be presented as a poster at the session: H32N - Causal Inference in Hydrology: Inter-comparisons, Applications, and Future Avenues at 9:00 AM - 12:30 PM on Wednesday, December 14. Welcome to stop by and discuss with me. If you are interested in this research and have any further questions or comments, please also feel free to contact me.</description>
    </item>
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>
