<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Mixed Methods on Beichen Zhang</title>
    <link>https://zhang-beichen.github.io/tags/mixed-methods/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mixed Methods on Beichen Zhang</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://zhang-beichen.github.io/tags/mixed-methods/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>AGU 2023 🌎</title>
      <link>https://zhang-beichen.github.io/blogs/agu2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zhang-beichen.github.io/blogs/agu2023/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;AGU Fall Meeting 2023 is coming. I will serve as a chair of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://eppro01.ativ.me/web/page.php?page=Session&amp;amp;project=AGU23&amp;amp;id=s203530-159926&#34;&gt;GeoHealth (GH23): Surviving the Dry Spell: Understanding the Connection Between Drought Health&lt;/a&gt;, which will be held from 14:10 to 15:40 on December 12. Here is the abstract of the session.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Drought is a natural disaster that can have a profound impact on the  environment, economy, and human health. Droughts can lead to food and  water scarcity, malnutrition, water-borne diseases, and increased  environmental hazards, such as smoke, dust, and heat. Moreover, droughts can exacerbate existing health conditions such as respiratory diseases, infectious diseases, and mental health problems. As droughts are  becoming more frequent and severe due to climate change, it is important to understand the relationships with health for improved public health  mitigation strategies. This session will bring together researchers,  public health officials, and policymakers to share their latest research findings and insights on the relationship between drought and human  health. The session will cover topics such as the direct and indirect  health impacts of drought, the mechanisms linking drought and health  outcomes, and effective strategies for reducing the negative effects of  drought on human health.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
