<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blog on Climate, Human, Data, &amp; Modeling</title><link>https://zhang-beichen.github.io/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Blog on Climate, Human, Data, &amp; Modeling</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://zhang-beichen.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>AGU Annual Meeting 2024</title><link>https://zhang-beichen.github.io/posts/agu2024/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zhang-beichen.github.io/posts/agu2024/</guid><description>AGU Fall Meeting 2024 is coming. This is the first professional and international conference attended after graduating and joining Berkeley Lab. I will present my postdoctoral work on developing a conceptual framework through literature review to evaluate inter-dependencies among energy transition &amp;amp; decarbonization pathways, natural resources, and environmental &amp;amp; social impacts. My colleague, Tamim, is the lead author of this task. In addition to assisting with its development, my primary role is to translate the conceptual framework into a quantitative model.</description></item><item><title>AGU Annual Meeting 2023</title><link>https://zhang-beichen.github.io/posts/agu2023/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zhang-beichen.github.io/posts/agu2023/</guid><description>AGU Fall Meeting 2023 is coming. I will serve as a chair of the GeoHealth (GH23): Surviving the Dry Spell: Understanding the Connection Between Drought Health, which will be held from 14:10 to 15:40 on December 12. Here is the abstract of the session.
Drought is a natural disaster that can have a profound impact on the environment, economy, and human health. Droughts can lead to food and water scarcity, malnutrition, water-borne diseases, and increased environmental hazards, such as smoke, dust, and heat.</description></item></channel></rss>